Guide to the East Asia Library, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
East Asia Library, Yale University, records
1946-2000
RU 1072
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8
(8 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, reports, and personnel files of the East Asia Library, Yale University.
Yale University. East Asia Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-D (YRG 32-D), Records of Yale school and departmental libraries and collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the East Asia Library, 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See finding aid for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, reports, and personnel files of the East Asia Library, Yale University.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Academic libraries -- Departmental libraries; East Asia -- Library resources; Yale University. East Asia Library -- Library
- East Asia Library records, 1946-2000; Accession 2008-A-139
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2036
  - East Asia Material Exchange, 1972-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 4)
  - University of Chicago, 1965-1996 (Box 1, Folder 5 - 6)
  - Selling analytical cards from collection, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - U.S. General, 1965-1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - East Asian Libraries in U.S. and Vital Statistics, 1959-1987 (Box 1, Folder 11 - 12)
  - Columbia Univ.-East Asia, 1960-1999 (Box 1, Folder 13 - 14)
  - Chinese Rare Books, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Yale E.A. Biblio Seminar, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Periodicals (Yale's East Asian Collection Lists), 1960-1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - China Mainland, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Special Japanese Materials, 1954-1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Annual Report Prep., 1969-2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - CALRFE (Com. on Amer. Lib. Resources on the Far East), 1958-1969 (Box 1, Folder 21 - 27)
  - Far Eastern Libraries in the U.S., 1946-1964 (Box 1, Folder 28 - 29)
  - East Asian Collection -letters to Librarians, 1949-1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - University of California (Los Angeles), 1966-1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Princeton University, 1984-1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Pinyin Romanization, 1988-2000 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - ROK(Rep. of Korea)Supreme Court, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - NOTIS CJK, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - RLIN CJK Hardware/Software, 1988-1994 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Microform Review, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - New York Public Library, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1977-1985 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - University of Michigan, 1979-1996 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Japan - U.S. Friendship Commission (10 university consortium), 1975-1992 (Box 2, Folder 42 - 44)
  - Library of Congress, 1974-1996 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - LC, Tokyo Office, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - University of Massachusetts, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Mellon Fund, 1972-1980 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - University of Illinois, 1978-1989 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - International Congress of Orientalists, 1967-1997 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - American Library Association/Assoc. of College and Research Lib/Assoc. for Asian Studies, 1975-1992 (Box 2, Folder 51 - 54)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1965-1999 (Box 2, Folder 55 - 56)
  - Chinese American Library Assoc., 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - U.S. Japan Conference on Cultural and Educational Interchange (CULCON), 1973-1993 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Duke University, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - East Coast East Asian Lib. Consortium, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - East Rock Institute, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Harvard-Yenching Library, 1973-1996 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Hawaii, University of, 1985-1994 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Hoover Institution, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1983-1995 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Art Library, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Council Meeting (CEAL Statistics), 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Visiting Japanese Scholars, 1972-1996 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Yale Classification, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Action Planning (East Asian Collection), 1993-1997 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - CEAL Annual Statistical Reports, 1973-1994 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Academia Sinica, 1963-1974 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - East Asian Studies Library Advisory Committee, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Collection Budget Current, and Requests, 1975-1999 (Box 3, Folder 79 - 80)
  - Council Proposals, 1972-1991 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Annual Report - EAC Staff, 1973-1994 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Conference on National Planning for Japanese Libraries, 1979-1991 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Budget Planning, 1966-1990 (Box 3, Folder 86 - 87)
  - Million dollar projects subjects approach, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Recommendations, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Annual Report, 1990-2000 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - CJK Recon I and II, 1994-1997 (Box 4, Folder 112 - 113)
  - Microfilm Materials - Subject (General), 1963-1994 (Box 4, Folder 114 - 115)
  - Microform, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Nihonmatsu, 1993-2000 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - AAS Subcommittee on Japanese Materials, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - CEAL(Committee on East Asian Libraries), 1968-1981 (Box 5, Folder 119 - 120)
  - Automation Conference(ACLS -American Council of Learned Societies), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - ACLS I and II, 1973-1981 (Box 5, Folder 122 - 123)
  - Yale Research Guide to East Asian Studies (Linda Lin Chang's report), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - Workshop for Japanese Collection Librarians, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 125)
  - Regional Conferences, 1982-1988 (Box 5, Folder 126)
  - NPTA(Nat. Planning Team for Academic Japanese Libraries)(Hoover Conference), 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 127 - 129)
  - U.S.-Japan Library Conferences (2, 3, 4th Seminar), 1972-1993 (Box 5, Folder 130 - 132)
  - US-Japan Library Liaison, 1967-1974 (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - Chinese Preservation Project, 1982-1988 (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - Sumitomo Group, 1973-1977 (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - Association for Asian Studies, 1961-1969 (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - Treasury, Dept. License, 1961-1978 (Box 5, Folder 137)
  - Japan Society, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - L.C.---Descriptive Cataloging Div., 1960-1975 (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - L.C.---Exchange and Gift Div., 1962-1979 (Box 5, Folder 141)
  - L.C.--Orientalia Div. (China), 1965-1978 (Box 5, Folder 142)
  - Special Purchases, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 143)
  - ALA-RTSD-CCS Far Eastern Materials Committee, 1957-1966 (Box 6, Folder 145)
  - National Institute of Japanese Literature Tokyo, 1978-1992 (Box 6, Folder 146)
  - American Library Assoc.---Library Resources and Technical Services (ALA-LRTS), 1959-1964 (Box 6, Folder 149 - 151)
  - ARL Foreign Acquisitions Project For Japanese Materials, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 152)
  - University Microfilm: Michigan, 1962-1972 (Box 6, Folder 153)
  - Rogers, Rutherford D., 1969-1976 (Box 6, Folder 155)
  - Japan-U.S. NY Conference, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 159)
  - Japanese Journals Project, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 160)
  - East Coast Japan Library Conference, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 161)
  - Current Serials, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 163)
  - Interdepartmental Policies, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 164)
  - East Asian Collections - Chinese and Japanese Catg. - Cooperative, 1958-1960 (Box 6, Folder 165)
  - RLG - East Asia, 1974-1998 (Box 6, Folder 166)
  - Chinese Libraries Consortium, 1984-1991 (Box 6, Folder 167)
  - Japan-U.S. Friendship Commission, 1982-1992 (Box 7, Folder 168 - 171)
  - East Coast Library Consortium, 1988-1994 (Box 7, Folder 172)
  - Chinese Cataloging Project, 1972-1978 (Box 7, Folder 173)
  - CEAL/STP (Subcommittee on Technical Processing), 1979-1981 (Box 7, Folder 174)
  - Bibliographical Guide to Chinese Works (1898-1937 by Fairbank and Liu), 1980 (Box 7, Folder 175)
  - Harvard University Libraries, 1961-1970 (Box 7, Folder 176)
  - Harvard University--East Asian Research Center, 1961-1972 (Box 7, Folder 177)
  - Cornell University, 1962-1977 (Box 7, Folder 178)
  - Connecticut College, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 179)
  - University of Rochester, 1967-1972 (Box 7, Folder 180)
  - Princeton University, 1962-1980 (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 182)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1972-1977 (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - Ohio State University Libraries, 1972-1984 (Box 7, Folder 184)
  - Oberlin College, 1968-69 (Box 7, Folder 185)
  - University of North Carolina, 1970-1977 (Box 7, Folder 186)
  - Harvard-Yenching Library, 1965-1976 (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - Wisconsin University, 1963-1975 (Box 7, Folder 188)
  - University of Washington (Seattle), 1959-1977 (Box 7, Folder 189)
  - Washington University (St. Louis), 1964-1977 (Box 7, Folder 190)
  - Stanford University - Hoover Institution, 1958-1976 (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - Indiana University, 1969-1974 (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - University of Illinois, 1966-76 (Box 7, Folder 193)
  - Hawaii University (East-West Center Lib.), 1965-1979 (Box 7, Folder 194)
  - University of Michigan, 1965-1993 (Box 7, Folder 195)
  - University of Maryland, 1963-1977 (Box 7, Folder 196)
  - Personnel: Staff Correspondence, 1962-1994 (Box 7, Folder 197)
  - Yale Library EAC, 1959-2000 (Box 8, Folder 199)
  - Weiying Wan - Acquisitions Policies, 1954-1995 (Box 8, Folder 201 - 202)
  - Custody and Scope of the Collection, 1959-1962 (Box 8, Folder 203)
  - Council on East Asian Studies, 1962-1984 (Box 8, Folder 207)
  - East Asia Reading Room, 1998-2000 (Box 8, Folder 208)
  - Cataloging, 1970-1973 (Box 8, Folder 209)
  - OCLC, 1993-2000 (Box 8, Folder 210)
  - Space Planning, 1991-1996 (Box 8, Folder 211)
  - RLG Survey, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 214)
  - Manuscripts and Archives, 1973-1997 (Box 8, Folder 215)
  - Special Resources at Yale, 1964-1968 (Box 8, Folder 216)
  - Curator - Trips, 1963-1978 (Box 8, Folder 217)
  - Preservation, 1982-1989 (Box 8, Folder 218)
  - Visitors, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 220)
  - Trip to Japan, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 221)
  - Divinity Library, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 222)
  - National Planning Team for Academic Japanese Libraries, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 223)
  - Religion, Policy for, 1972-1992 (Box 8, Folder 224)
  - Trips to China, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 225)
  - Manuscripts, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 226)
  - Card Catalogue, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 227)
  - Reappraisal of Japanese Collections inWestern Countries, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 228)
  - Association of Yale Alumni, 1981-1989 (Box 8, Folder 229)
  - Henry R. Luce International Center, 1980-1997 (Box 8, Folder 230)
  - Art Gallery, Yale, 1977-1990 (Box 8, Folder 231)
  - Rare Books, Processing of, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 232)
  - Surveys, Japanese Acquisitions Survey, Survey Reports, 1974-1989 (Box 8, Folder 233 - 235)
  - Yale University Archives, 1965-1973 (Box 8, Folder 236)
  - Security, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 237)
  - Reference, 1975-1997 (Box 8, Folder 238)